<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>e64</title>
    <description>The website/blog of Epitaph64 / Enzor.</description>
    <link>http://e64.us/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://e64.us/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 20:12:28 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 20:12:28 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>HTML 5 Game Development Experiments</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;play-the-game-a-hrefgamespeg-pilferer-click-here-abrbr&quot;&gt;Play the game: &lt;a href=&quot;/games/peg-pilferer/&quot;&gt;[ Click Here ]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After finishing the &lt;a href=&quot;/website/project/2016/01/08/project-complete-engr-website.html&quot;&gt;engineering class website&lt;/a&gt; I was tasked to work on over winter break,
I decided to use the last week of vacation to improve my JavaScript skills. I decided working on a simple
game would be a nice way to relax and still get some programming practice in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had used &lt;a href=&quot;http://phaser.io/&quot;&gt;Phaser&lt;/a&gt; in the past for CactusHack 2015
(hosted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/TucsonJS/&quot;&gt;TucsonJS&lt;/a&gt;) where my group
managed to take 2nd place thanks to our bravery in attempting a game in 24 hours.
I suppose participating in &lt;a href=&quot;http://ludumdare.com/compo/&quot;&gt;LudumDare&lt;/a&gt; events in the past has given me a bit of agility
when it comes to learning new game frameworks and implementing basic gameplay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly Phaser, despite having a lot of great features built in, suffers from a lack
of up to date documentation and demo code. Additionally, because the library seems to have
undergone quite a lot of change over time, many of the internet searches I performed while looking
for basic functionality were for older versions of the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I decided that I ought to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pixijs.com/&quot;&gt;Pixi.JS&lt;/a&gt; (the library that Phaser is built
on top of) upon hearing chatter around the internet that it was a much better library
than Phaser, although being a bit harder to learn initially.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I’ve found, however, is that Pixi.JS is much more intuitively designed, and performs
much better for games that involve simple logic. After spending about 3-4 hours with the library
I’ve created a very simple game &lt;a href=&quot;/games/peg-pilferer/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;
to demonstrate what is possible. I however did use the wonderful &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/peterolson/BigInteger.js&quot;&gt;
BigInteger&lt;/a&gt; library by Peter Olson to allow quick score calculation and to store the large
resulting integer for the later stages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2016 03:34:16 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://e64.us/html5/game/programming/2016/01/12/html-5-simple-game-tutorial.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://e64.us/html5/game/programming/2016/01/12/html-5-simple-game-tutorial.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>html5</category>
        
        <category>game</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Engineering Class Website Complete!</title>
        <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;the-deliverables&quot;&gt;The Deliverables&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While some additional features remain to be worked on, the launch version of the ECE 535
class website has been deployed and is operational at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www2.engr.arizona.edu/~vasicteach/teaching/ece535a/&quot;&gt;this location&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;backstory&quot;&gt;Backstory&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend and mentor Dr. Bane Vasić came to me a couple of months ago requesting a redesign for his class website before the upcoming semester. Having just learned Jekyll for use in my own personal website (which you’re hopefully reading this post on right now), I suggested it after determining that there would be no immediate need for a database and convincing him that he would be able to learn the YML and Markdown languages without much difficulty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After gaining his approval I set off and built a basic prototype to show how the site could be organized using the stock layout, and how I could modify it to fit the requirements of the project. We had a few issues with the first prototypes and getting them to build on his system. However, after some coaxing we were able to get the site to build on both of our machines and all was well. Despite the initial rocky sell on the framework, we decided to press forward as the results we had seen looked promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that I spent a week or so porting over the content he wished to reuse from a past iteration of the class, and then organized the site’s data in YML data files in order to make the site easy to edit in the future. I also worked on writing a collection of bash scripts to create a new post, deploy the site using rsync, and various other administrative tasks that will be involved in running the site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I had a good experience with Jeyll and have learned many things which I will surely make use of in improving my own site in the future. Additionally, I have even begun lurking Jekyll’s GitHub page to see what types of features are being worked on. Perhaps I may even try to contribute in the future!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 13:32:11 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://e64.us/website/project/2016/01/08/project-complete-engr-website.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://e64.us/website/project/2016/01/08/project-complete-engr-website.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>project</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Website Redesign</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve gone ahead and decided to start using Jekyll to work on my blog. Although there were
a few hitches in getting it setup, I am really enjoying using Markdown and the Liquid Templating language.
Although the site is being compiled to static HTML to be served on Github, it almost feels
like I am working on a dynamic site due to the power of the included technologies in the framework.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Oct 2015 12:31:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://e64.us/website/blog/2015/10/22/new-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://e64.us/website/blog/2015/10/22/new-blog.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>website</category>
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
